字　　幕　　侠
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
THE SUB-MAN
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
顶   峰   娱   乐
总监　皮带断了
狮 门 电 影 公 司
THE SUB-MAN
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
纽约市民们 暴风雨似乎已经过去
It looks like the storm has passed.
昨晚降雨量达到178毫米的历史峰值
New Yorkers, a season high, seven inches of rain last night.
部分地区遭大风和洪水侵袭
High winds and flooding in some areas
导致一些市民生活陷入困境
even left some New Yorkers stranded.
市政部门今早仍在全力工作
City crews still working this morning.
努力恢复受灾地区电力供应
They're trying to restore power to several areas
好消息是 今日阳光明媚 最低气温16摄氏度
Good news is, today should be sunny with highs in the low 60s.
恶劣天气持续了几周
Relentless weather these past few weeks.
所以 出去走走 享受阳光
So get out there, enjoy the sun,
有条件的去逛逛公园
go to the park, get outside if you can,
这种好天气可不会持续很久
because it's not gonna last long.
你在干什么 约翰
What are you doing, John?
在看你啊
Looking at you.
过来
Come here.
还在拍吗
Are you still filming?
疾速追杀
周年纪念礼
Just an anniversary...
好久不见
It's been a while.
节哀
My condolences.
你怎么样了
How're you holdin' up?
我一直在想 "为什么是她"
I keep asking "Why her?"
人生无常 世事难料
There's no rhyme or reason to this life.
今天只是悠悠岁月的一点缩影
It's days like today scattered among the rest.
是吗
Are you sure?
别再自责了
Don't blame yourself.
你到底在这干什么 马库斯
What are you really doing here, Marcus?
只是来看看老朋友
Just checkin' up on an old friend.
再见 约翰
Goodbye, John.
是约翰·维克吗
John Wick?
是我
Yes.
请在这签字
Sign here, please.
我的笔
And the pen.
不好意思
Sorry.
- 可以了 晚安 - 谢谢
-Here you go. Good night. -Thanks.
凯文
速递服务
约翰 很抱歉不能继续相伴
"John, I'm sorry I can't be there for you.
但你依然需要去爱某个人 爱某样东西
But you still need something, someone, to love.
那就从它开始吧 你那辆车可不算
So start with this. Because the car doesn't count.
我爱你 约翰
I love you, John.
我们都被病魔折磨了太久
This illness has loomed over us for a long time,
现在我内心已经平静 希望你也一样
And now that I have found my peace, find yours.
永远都是你最好的朋友 海伦"
"Until that day, your best friend, Helen."
黛西
Daisy.
挺好听
Of course.
来吧
Come on.
我醒了 马上起
I'm up. I'm up...
起了 起了
I'm up. I'm up.
好吧
Right.
怎么了
What?
晚点再买狗粮给你
We'll grab you some kibble later.
车不错
Nice ride.
野马
Mustang.
博思 429
Boss 429.
70年款吗
She a '70?
69年的
'69.
不错
Huh.
很炫酷
Beautiful car.
谢谢
Thanks.
多少钱
How much?
什么意思
Excuse me?
这车卖多少钱
How much for the car?
谁说要卖了
She's not for sale.
我喜欢狗狗
Oh, I love dogs.
任何东西都有个价的 傻逼
这傻逼没有
这货以为他是谁啊！
先生 祝你愉快
You have good day, sir.
好吧 快上来
All right, come on, then.
感觉怎么样
How you doin'?
你要出去吗
You need to go?
那该死的汽车钥匙在哪？
宰了那该死的狗！
快找钥匙
在这呢 我找到钥匙了
晚安了 傻逼
这玩意现在是我的了！
奥雷利奥
Yo, Aurelio!
怎么
Ah?
给我换个新牌照 再给我办个合法证件
I want a new VIN number and some clean papers.
这车你从哪里搞来的
Where'd you get that car?
车在这吗
Is it here?
之前在这
It was.
我问你他妈的从哪搞来的这车
I asked you where the hell did you get it?
关你屁事
who give a shit.
尤瑟夫·塔拉索夫偷的
Iosef Tarasov nicked it.
维果的儿子
Viggo's son.
是的
Yeah.
好吧 给老子滚
All right, get out of here.
从我店里滚出去 立刻滚
Just get out of my shop. Get out right now.
你胆儿挺肥的 奥雷利奥
Did you just lose your shit, Aurelio?
你归我们管
Because we own you.
你说什么 你丫再说一遍
What did you say? What did you say to me?
你归我们管
We own you.
你管不着我 傻缺
You don't own me, punk.
我和你父亲共事 懂吗
I work with your father, all right?
你是不是把车主杀了
The owner of that car, did you kill him or what?
没
No.
不过我搞死了他的狗
I sure as hell fucked up his dog.
搞死他的狗 你就这点出息吗
You fucked up his dog? That's what you did?
你搞死了他的狗
You fucked up his dog?
是啊
Yeah...
真他妈扯蛋
That's crazy shit, man.
瞧瞧 你们够屌
Aw, look at you. That's great.
进了我的店 还拿枪指着我
You're gonna come into my shop and you're gonna pull a gun on me.
不错啊 来吧
Ah, that's great, man. Come on!
听着 要么你杀了我
Now, either you kill me right now
要么从我店里滚出去
or you get the fuck outta my shop!
这样维果会不高兴的
Viggo is not gonna like this.
你又知道维果会不会高兴
How do you know what Viggo likes or doesn't like?
我告诉你他肯定会了解状况
I'll tell you somethin' he's gonna understand.
你他妈惹到我了 老逼
You've got a fuckin' pair on you, old man!
看来得去别处搞定这事了
I guess we'll be takin' our business someplace else.
你打算怎么做
So what are you gonna do?
我需要一台车
I need a ride.
我是奥雷利奥
Aurelio is speaking
听说你打了我儿子
I heard you struck my son.
没错 先生 是我揍的
Yes sir, I did.
给我一个理由
And may I ask why?
他偷了约翰·维克的车 先生
Yeah. Well, because he stole John Wick's car, sir.
还弄死他的狗
And, uh, killed his dog.
好吧
Oh.
维果
Viggo?
怎么了
Yeah?
他们答应你的条件了
They've agreed to your terms.
况且 你也没给他们太多
I mean, it's not like you gave them much
选择的余地 对吧
of a choice anyway, though, right?
恭喜
Congratulations.
先生
Sir?
你见过我儿子吗
Have you seen my son?
旅途愉快吗 孩子
How was your trip, kid?
我们很快不会再听到他们消息了
We won't be hearing from them anytime soon.
或者永远听不到
Or ever.
夹克不错
That's a nice jacket.
- 谢谢
- 真的不错
-Thanks. -Yeah.
擦干净
我该走了吗
Should I go?
维果 说英语
Viggo, English, please. Come on...
留在这 该死
Stay, God damn it!
我做错了什么
What did I do?
你搞砸了
都是按你要求做的
We did what you asked.
没被任何人看见
No one saw shit.
我没说大西洋城的事
I'm not talking about Altantic City.
那你说的什么
What, then?
是说奥雷利奥吗 我他妈只偷了辆车
You mean Aurelio's? So I stole a fucking car!
妈的 维果
Aw, fuck, Viggo!
00:22:56,642 --> 00:22:58,602
-我得走了  -不许走
-Right, I'll go...  -You stay!
儿子 你做什么倒没让我恼火
It's not what you did, son, that angers me so.
让我恼火的是你对谁做了
It's who you did it to.
谁 那人算条毛
Who? The fucking nobody!
你惹的 "这条毛"
That fuckin' nobody
是约翰·维克
is John Wick.
他曾是我们的一员
He once was an associate of ours.
人称 "巴巴亚加"
They call him Baba Yaga.
夜魔
The Boogeyman?
当然 他不是真的夜魔
Well, John wasn't exactly The Boogeyman.
他是你派去杀夜魔的那个人
He was the one you sent to kill the fucking Boogeyman.
约翰做事专注
John is a man of focus,
言出必行
commitment,
意志坚定
sheer will.
这些品质你几乎没有
Something you know very little about.
我见过他在酒吧连杀三人
I once saw him kill three men in a bar.
只用一只铅笔
With a pencil.
只用了他妈的
With a fuckin'...
一只铅笔
...pencil.
后来有天他突然要求离开
Then suddenly one day he asked to leave.
因为某个女人
It's over a woman, of course.
所以我们达成一条协议
So I made a deal with him.
我给他一项不可能完成的任务
I gave him an impossible task.
任何人都无法完成的任务
A job no one could have pulled off.
他那天埋的尸体
The bodies he buried that day
奠定了我们现在地位的基础
laid the foundation of what we are now.
后来
And then, my son,
他妻子死了没几天
a few days after his wife died,
你就偷他的车
you steal his car
还他妈弄死他的狗
and kill his fuckin' dog.
父亲 我可以补救的
Father, I can make this right.
是吗
Oh...
你有什么打算
How do you plan that?
一人做事一人当
By finishing what I started.
你他妈... 到底他听没听懂我的话
What the... Did he hear a fucking word I said?
父亲 我可以的 给我一个机会!
尤瑟夫 听着
Iosef! Iosef! Listen!
约翰要来找你算账了
John will come for you.
你什么也别做了
And you will do nothing,
因为你什么都做不了
because you can do nothing.
赶紧从我面前消失
So get the fuck out of my sight!
你好 约翰
Hello, John.
我听说了你妻子的事 我也很难过
I heard about your wife, and I'm sorry.
节哀吧
My condolences.
或许是天意 或许是偶然
It seems to be fate, or happenstance
或是倒他妈的霉 让我们再度相遇
or just bad fuckin' luck caused our paths to cross once again.
约翰
John?
我们不能再冲动行事了
Let us not resort to our baser instincts
要用文明的方式来处理 早点息事宁人
and handle this like civilized men, to move on...
他说什么
What'd he say?
他的态度很明确了
Enough.
惨了
Oh, God.
找人做事吧
Task your crew.
要多少人
How many?
你有多少人
How many do you have?
夜魔
睡吧孩子吧 不然             会找上门来
他会从夜的沼泽里爬出来
专门来             不乖的孩子
抓走
夜魔来了
晚上好 约翰
Evenin', John.
晚上好 吉米
Evenin', Jimmy.
有人投诉噪音吗
Noise complaint?
是的 噪音投诉
Noise complaint.
重操旧业了
You, uh, workin' again?
没有 整理东西而已
No, just sortin' some stuff out.
好吧
Ah, well...
那你自己处理吧
I'll leave you be, then.
晚安 约翰
Good night, John.
晚安 吉米
Good night, Jimmy.
我是维克
This is Wick.
是的 约翰·维克 没错
Yes, John Wick, that's right.
我要预定12人份的晚餐
I'd like to make a dinner reservation for 12.
很高兴见到你 约翰
Good to see you, John.
我也是 查理
Charlie.
专业废物处理
你看起来不错
You look good.
我以为你早就金盆洗手了
And here I'd feared you'd left all this behind.
以后还会再联系吗
Will I be hearin' from you anytime soon?
再见 查理
Goodbye, Charlie.
再见 约翰
John.
他果然不好惹
Of course he did.
发个约翰·维克的暗杀悬赏
Put a contract on John Wick.
出价多少
How much?
两百万美元
Two million.
舍不得孩子
套不着
狼
维果 说英语
English, Viggo, please.
让尤瑟夫在红圈俱乐部等着 我们蹲守
Put Iosef in the Red Circle and wait.
要干嘛
For what?
当然是要杀约翰·维克
For John Wick, of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
这次找我有什么事
To what do I owe this visit?
我有个活儿要给你
I have a job for you.
怎么不打电话
And I've got a phone.
你可能会觉得这是私事
I want to offer you this face to face
所以我想和你面谈
seeing as how you might find it personal.
给你两百万 能杀了约翰·维克吗
Would you kill John Wick for two million dollars?
毕竟你们以前很熟
After all, you were close.
独家合约吗
Is the contract exclusive?
谁都能接
No, it's open.
只是任务紧急 必须赶快解决他
It's a timely matter, it has to be handled quickly.
包在我身上
Consider it done.
谢谢你 马库斯
Thank you, Marcus.
我就知道你信的过 谢谢你的饮料
I know I can trust you. Thanks for the drink.
♪这个世界需要歌剧♪
This world doesn't need no opera
♪我们为了操作经营而需要它♪
We need it for the operation
♪我们不需要一把更大的刀♪
We don't need a bigger knife (a bigger knife)
♪因为我们有枪 我们有枪 我们有枪♪
Cause we got guns, we got guns, we got guns (we got guns)
♪我们有枪 你最好快逃♪
We got guns, you better run
♪你最好快逃 快逃快逃♪
you better run, you better run, you better run
♪我们正在杀害陌生人♪
We're killing strangers, we're killing strangers
♪我们杀陌生人 因为我们不杀所爱之人♪
We're killing strangers, so we don't kill the ones that we love
♪我们正在杀害陌生人♪
We're killing strangers, we're killing strangers
♪我们杀陌生人 因为我们不杀所爱之人♪
We're killing strangers, so we don't kill the ones that we love
918房间 祝您入住愉快
Room 918. Do enjoy your stay.
谢谢
Thanks.
很高兴又见面了 约翰
Good seeing you again, John.
我也是 珀金斯
Perkins.
给你安排两晚如何
I have you for two nights.
看情况 可能会多住几天
Depending on business, it may be more.
没问题 先生
Of course, sir.
这老地方什么时候焕然一新了
So when did the old place get a facelift?
大概4年前
Around four years ago.
有点我可以肯定 她真的变化不大
But I assure you, sir, she really hasn't changed much.
还是老东家吗
Same owner?
还是老东家
Same owner.
818房
Room 818.
老规矩
And, as always,
您再次光临我们深感荣幸 维克先生
it is a pleasure having you with us again, Mr. Wick.
你在干什么 约翰
What are you doing, John?
我在看你
Looking at you.
过来
Come here.
你好 温斯顿
Hello, Winston.
乔纳森
Jonathan.
在我的印象里
Now, as I recall,
你是派人去揍人的家伙
weren't you the one tasked to dole out
而不是挨揍的那个人
the beatings, not receive them?
老了 不行啦
Rusty, I guess.
找我什么事
To what do we owe the pleasure?
尤瑟夫·塔拉索夫
Iosef Tarasov.
他怎么了
What about him?
我想和他谈谈
I'd like to talk with him.
你是说 谈谈
A talk, you say.
我了解说话的语调 乔纳森
I'm familiar with the parlance, Jonathan.
我就是想问问你
I want to ask you this.
你真的收手了吗
Have you returned to the fold?
去拜访而已
Just visiting.
你想清楚没有
Have you thought this through?
我是说 认认真真地想
I mean, chewed down to the bone?
你好不容易隐退
You got out once.
这浑水里哪怕你只陷入小指头这么浅
You dip so much as a pinky back into this pond,
很快就会有东西冒出来
you may well find something reaches out
把你拖进无尽深渊
and drags you back into its depths.
哪里能找到他
Where do I find him?
维克在大陆酒店
Wick's at The Continental.
欢迎回来 约翰
Welcome home, John.
那里有人愿意接受悬赏替我们除掉他
We have a contact there who's willing to take him out for us.
怎么样
Yeah?
真不要脸
How brazen.
如果他们要破坏大陆酒店的规矩
If they're willing to break the rules of Continental,
我就把赏金翻倍
double the bounty.
你懂规矩的
You know the rules.
规矩在此 没人敢接
No business can be conducted on these premises
都怕遭到重罚
lest incurring heavy penalties.
喝一杯吧
Have a drink
暂时
and relax.
放松一下
For now.
私人恩怨
It's personal.
天呐 乔纳森
Holy shit! Jonathan!
- 嘿阿迪
- 老天爷
-Hey, Addy. -My God!
多年不见 有4年了吧
How long has it been? Four years?
5年多吧
Five and change.
说说看 普通人生活是啥样的
So tell me, how was life on the other side?
挺好的 阿迪
It was good, Addy.
比我预想的好很多
Far better than I deserved.
我很遗憾 听说你的…
Hey, I'm sorry to hear about your...
谢了
Thanks.
我从没见你像现在这样
I've never seen you like this.
哪样
Like what?
脆弱
Vulnerable.
我退休了
I'm retired.
只要你在这儿喝酒 你就没有退
Not if you're drinkin' here, you're not.
- 老规矩吗
- 没错
-Usual? -Please.
老板请客
Compliments of the house.
谢谢
Thanks.
红圈俱乐部
二楼 汇报你那边情况
VIP房间一切正常
阳台 有可疑情况吗?
没有维克的踪影
地下室
下面情况如何?
地下室 没有异常
你看见那妹子的咪咪没
Did you see the tits on that girl?
最好今晚丽塔在上班
Better hope Lita is working tonight.
下来哥们 跟我们一起喝一杯
我的职责是保证一个小屁孩的安全 不是给一个酒鬼当保姆
你是害怕那该死的夜魔吗
Are you scared of the fuckin' boogeyman?
我可不怕
I'm not.
你不怕吗 你应该怕才对
No. But you should be.
给我再来瓶酒
I want another bottle!
你他妈还不快去 再给我拿一瓶来
Right fuckin' now! Go get me a bottle!
去啊
Come on!
你好 弗朗西斯
Hello, Francis.
维克先生
Mr. Wick.
你瘦了
瘦了
六十
磅
是嘛？
真了不起
你来这儿是不是有活要干 先生
Are you here on business, sir?
恐怕是的 弗朗西斯
Afraid so, Francis.
你今晚不如休息
Why don't you take the night off.
了解 先生
Thank you, sir.
尤瑟夫
在哪里？
操你妈的 混蛋
Fuck you, motherfucker!
尤瑟夫在哪
Where is Iosef?
在楼下的浴房
Bath house, downstairs.
偷了
是你　　 　我的车
而且
你还杀了
我的狗
去你妈
有约翰·维克的踪影吗？
没有发现
二楼 报告情况
地下室 一切正常？
是的
他在
这儿！
快走
Go!
跟着
我上!
约翰·维克来了 去干掉他
John Wick's there. Go get him!
维克在
这儿！
他就在
维克在
这儿！
这栋楼里！
他就在
快去 他在这儿 他妈就在那边
Move! He's here! He's fucking here!
在那 他来了
He's there! He's coming!
进来 快上车
Get in! Get in!
快点 走了
Come on, come on!
维克多  你
他妈
在哪儿？
维克多已经
死了
凡事都要
付出
代价
晚上好 维克先生
Good evening, Mr. Wick.
晚上好
Good evening.
能为您效劳吗
How may I be of service?
医生在不在
Is the doctor in?
在的 先生 全天候服务
Yes, sir. 24/7.
- 麻烦请他上来
- 好的先生
-Then send him up, please. -Yes, sir.
你们的洗衣服务质量如何
How good's your laundry?
实在抱歉 再好也没办法洗得那么干净
I'm sorry to say that no one's that good.
我想可以的
No. I thought not.
喝点什么吗 先生
May I suggest a drink, sir.
波旁威士忌 如何
Bourbon, perhaps.
听起来不错
That sounds perfect.
这算哪种缝合术
So what sort of movement am I looking at?
如果你想伤口愈合
Well, if you're lookin' to heal,
就别管这么多
then keep it marginal.
但是 如果你一会
However, if you still have...
还有事情要处理的话
...business to attend to,
先吃两片这个
take two of these beforehand.
这样即便伤口撕裂流血
Your stitches'll tear and you'll bleed,
你的身体机能也不会受影响
but you'll have full function.
需要镇痛药吗
Do you need anything for the pain?
不用 有酒就行
No, I've got that covered.
嘿 约翰
Hey, John.
珀金斯
Perkins?
我不请自来了
I thought I'd let myself in.
我知道
I noticed.
据我所知 想请帕金斯小姐出山至少要花三个金币
I never knew Ms. Perkins to get out of bed for less than three.
维果出价四个金币让我破坏酒店规矩
Viggo's giving me four to break hotel rules.
这不明智 我向你保证
That's unwise, I assure you.
你就是个娘炮
You were always a pussy.
有事吗
Yes?
很抱歉这个时间还打您电话
I apologize for calling you at this hour,
但你那层楼很多人
but we have received a number of grievances
来电抱怨说那里很吵
from your floor concerning the noise.
很抱歉
My apologies.
我刚刚在接待一个不速之客
I was dealing with an uninvited guest.
那么 您是不是有可能需要
Have you need then of, say,
预定晚餐呢
a dinner reservation, perhaps?
有可能 要的话我再打给你
Perhaps. I'll have to get back to you.
不要
No!
尤瑟夫在哪儿
Where's Iosef?
去你妈的
Fuck you.
维果在哪儿
Where's Viggo?
我什么都不会说的
I'm not telling you shit!
你真的想死这儿吗 珀金斯
Do you really wanna die here, Perkins?
说话
Give me somethin'.
在小俄罗斯
Little Russia.
加农法庭附近的一个教堂里
There's a church near Cannon Court.
那教堂是什么地方
What about it?
是个基地
It's a front.
维果把他个人物品都藏在那儿
It's where Viggo keeps his private stash.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们认识吗
Do I know you?
应该认识吧
I'm thinkin' so.
嘿 约翰
Hey, John.
嘿 哈里
Hey, Harry.
没什么事儿吧
Everything all right?
没事
Yeah. Everything's fine.
那你就自己解决吧
I'll leave you to it, then.
嘿 哈里
Hey, Harry?
想不想挣一枚金币
You keen on earning a coin?
帮我照顾好这个睡着的家伙
Babysittin' the sleepin' one?
抓了再放吗
Catch and release?
没错 猫鼠游戏
Catch and release.
孩子 我能为你做点什么吗
My son, how might I help you?
去你妈的
Motherfucker!
你知道你
他妈
惹得是谁吗？
知道
我清楚的很
带我去地下室
Let's go to the vault.
开门
Open it.
你以为你
威胁我
我就会开门吗？
你以为你
威胁我
我就会开门吗？
是的
快开门
维果会杀了我
Viggo will kill me.
然后
Uh-huh.
女士们 都出去
Ladies, out.
祝您愉快
老实说
Honestly,
你觉得你能怎么处理这堆东西
what do you think you're going to do with all of that?
像这样
This.
把那
给我带过来！
蠢货
别担心
Don't worry.
清洁工会发现你
Housekeeping will find you.
你对女士都这么粗暴吗
Treat all your ladies like this?
你可不是什么女士
You are no lady. Trust me.
哈利 那个是
Harry, is it?
你想不想得到不止一个金币的报酬
How'd you like to earn more than just a gold coin?
你坏了规矩
You've broken the rules.
你在大陆酒店的地盘上接活了
You've done business on Continental grounds.
管理层可不待见这种做法
And management does not take kindly to that sort of behavior.
去你妈的管理层
Fuck management.
没事 清洁工会发现你的
Don't worry. Housekeeping will find you.
妈的!
全烧成灰了
Ashes to ashes.
我们还能补救吗
Can we recover from this?
维果 你知道地下室里放的是什么吧
Viggo, you know what was in that vault, right?
那些算不上什么
It was nothing.
妈的
Shit!
上啊
Come on!
掩护我！
这么说吧 约翰
I'll say this, John.
他们肯定会把你碎尸万段
They sure as fuck broke the mold with you.
哎 呀
Ay, ay...
你好像一直都是
You always had a certain...
像吃了熊心豹胆似的
...audacity about you, you know.
是吧 哎
Right? Oh, yeah.
我想说 你还是老样子
I can say you're still very much the John Wick of old.
是吗
Am I?
人都是死性不改 你懂的
People don't change. You know that.
只有时间才会变化
Times, they do.
你知道那个地下室里有什么吗
Do you know what was in that vault?
艺术品 钞票 那些都无所谓
Artwork, cash, not without its worth,
但是录音 物证 勒索证据
but the leverage I had on this city,
这些我用来控制这个城市的手段
audio recordings, physical evidence, blackmail,
都是他妈的无价之宝啊
it was fuckin' priceless!
买都买不来的
Priceless!
是啊 我蛮享受的
Yeah. I kind of enjoyed that.
是嘛 我知道你是爽
Yeah, I know you did.
是啊
Yeah.
你还真的在笑啊
Are you really laughing?
说起来
So...
后来你结婚了 安定下来
Then you got married, ah? Settled down.
你到底是怎么做到的
How did you manage that anyways?
运气好吧
Luck, I guess.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊 你有老婆 我有儿子
Yeah, while you had your wife, I had my son.
相信我 你这生意做得不错
And believe me, you had a far better deal.
后来你隐退了
And then you left.
你用离开这种方式安慰你自己
And the way you got out,
过去的事对将来毫无影响
lying to yourself that the past held no sway over the future.
但是最终
But in the end,
出来混总是要还的
a lot of us are rewarded for our misdeeds,
这就是为何上帝带走你的妻子
which is why God took your wife
又把无所牵挂的你放在我面前
and unleashed you upon me.
这种命运如影随形
This life follows you.
你无从逃避
It clings to you,
任何你亲近的人都会被牵扯进来
infecting everyone who comes close to you.
我们被诅咒了 你和我都是
We are cursed, you and I.
这点我倒是认同
On that we agree.
我们终于有共识了
Finally, common ground.
好吧
Okay.
你闪一边去
Step aside.
把你儿子交给我
Give me your son.
约翰·维克
John Wick.
小 夜 魔
就因为一辆破车和一条蠢狗
It was just a fucking car! Just a fuckin' dog!
只是一条狗
Just a dog...
维果
Viggo?
怎么
Yeah.
海伦去世时 我已了无牵挂
When Helen died, I lost everything.
直到那只狗来到了我门前
Until that dog arrived on my doorstep.
那是妻子送给我的最后的礼物
A final gift from my wife.
那时我似乎又有了那么点希望
In that moment, I received some semblance of hope.
让我不再独自痛苦
An opportunity to grieve unalone.
但你儿子
And your son
把我那一丁点的希望都夺走了
took that from me!
拜托
Oh, come on...
偷走了我最后的希望
Stole that from me!
扼杀了我最后的希望
Killed that from me!
大家一直在问我是否还会回来接活
People keep asking if I'm back.
我一直没有想好
And I haven't really had an answer.
可现在 我想我回来了
But now, yeah, I'm thinkin' I'm back!
要么你主动交出你的儿子
So you can either hand over your son...
要么你就在他的尸体旁尖叫至死吧
...or you can die screaming alongside him!
冷静 冷静  别激动 别激动
Cool it, cool it, cool it, cool it, cool it!
约翰
John!
- 他在哪
- 该死
Where is he? Shit.
去他妈的
Shit!
你跟我保证 如果我说出他在哪
I have your word that if I tell you where he is,
你就放我走
you'll let me walk away?
收回对我的暗杀悬赏
Pull the contract.
成交
Done.
他躲在布鲁克林的一个安全屋里
He's kept in a safe house. Brooklyn.
华莱士住所 434号
434 Wallace Place.
他们知道你会去
They know you're coming.
废话
Of course.
知道了也无所谓
But it won't matter.
三号位
已就位
所有
位置
准备
待命
所有
位置
准备
待命
二号位
已就位
你别玩这操蛋的游戏了
Will you stop playing the fucking video game?
二号位
已就位
三号位
就位
你他妈不要再玩这操蛋的游戏了
Will you stop playing that fucking video game?
趴下 趴下
Get down, get down!
快 趴下 趴下
Come on, come on! Get down, get down!
那只不过是一只
该死的 . . .
给我安排一下
Make the arrangements.
谢谢
Thank you.
荣幸之至 先生
Our pleasure, sir.
这是管理层送的一份送别礼物
A parting gift. From the management.
用来补偿昨晚发生的
Compensation for last night's unfortunate
不幸事故
incident.
我还要救你多少次
How many times do I have to save your ass?
我很感激
I appreciate it.
当然
Of course.
你看起来很糟糕
You look terrible.
这是我退休的样子
No, I look retired.
退休
Retired?
你还信这个
You really believe that?
你有了新生活
You made a new life.
你会有办法重回生活的轨道
You'll find your way back to it.
该回家了
It's time to go home.
不管你们想干啥 都他妈来吧
Let's get on with this, whatever the fuck this is.
你好 马库斯
Hello, Marcus.
我是约翰
This is John.
感谢你让我儿子死了个痛快
I appreciate you granting my son a swift death.
我不知道该怎么回报你
I wouldn't know how to reply to that either.
马库斯背叛了我
Marcus betrayed me.
你已经收回了暗杀悬赏
You pulled the contract.
暗杀悬赏有效时 你有很多机会
And while it was open, you had every chance,
有很多时机杀了约翰·维克
every opportunity to kill John Wick.
如果你做了你该做的
And if you had done your job,
我儿子现在应该还活着
my son would be still alive!
他这么做
And in so doing,
违背了基本原则
he broke the cardinal rule.
谢谢
Thank you.
珀金斯小姐
Ms. Perkins.
为什么我一点也不惊讶呢
Why am I not surprised?
正所谓一不做二不休
In for a penny, in for a pound.
所以 我也没得选择
So, John, I had no choice.
我一直都很喜欢你 马库斯
I always liked you, Marcus.
最后一个守旧者
The last of the old guard.
但是和别人不同 你得按照我的方式死
But unlike the others, you go out on my terms.
天啊 别
God! No!
不 我的好先生
No, my good sir.
我按照我自己的方式死
I go out on my own.
♪我们正在杀害陌生人♪
We're killing strangers, we're killing strangers
♪我们杀陌生人 因为我们不杀所爱之人♪
We're killing strangers, so we don't kill the ones that we love
♪爱 爱 爱♪
Love, love, love
我说得对吧
See?
♪你最好快逃 因为我们有枪 我们有枪♪
You better run, cause we got guns, we got guns...
干得漂亮 老朋友
Well played, old friend.
我们搞完了吗 维果
We done, Viggo?
搞完了
We're done.
好的 你的衣服
Okay. Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
是的 给直升机加满油
Yeah. Fuel the chopper.
珀金斯小姐 很抱歉这个时候给你来电
Ms. Perkins, I apologize for calling you at this hour.
珀金斯小姐
Ms. Perkins,
鉴于你的所为
your membership to the Continental has been,
你在大陆酒店的会员资格被取消
by thine own hand, revoked.
我知道你在想什么 乔纳森
I know what you're thinking, Jonathan.
我们都有自己的做事原则
We live by a code.
所以我不会告诉你
Which is why I'm not the one telling you that
在某个直升机场有架直升机
a certain helicopter at a certain helipad
加满了油正在等着某人
is being fueled for a certain someone.
我的香烟是不是在你那
Have you got my cigarettes?
是在我这儿
Yeah, I got your cigarettes.
谁在后面
跟着我们?
我操
Oh, fuck!
妈的 这下好了 开快点
Yeah. Super. Come on, let's go. Faster!
直升机就在前面 来吧 快点走
The helicopter's right down there. Come on! Let's go!
我操
Oh, shit!
操他妈的 我就知道他会来
Goddamn, I knew he'd come.
这混蛋有什么毛病
What's fuckin' wrong with this guy?
你们谁给我一支枪 谁有枪
Somebody give me a gun. Who's got a gun?
天啦
Oh, God!
刚刚那下撞得不错
That was a good one.
谁有枪
Who's got a gun?
去
干掉他!
操
Fuck!
维果 直升机 就在那边
Viggo, the helicopters, right over there.
我们必须得熬到那边
We have to get over there.
天呐 我需要一支枪
Oh, my God, I need a gun.
说英语行吗
English, please.
祝你好运
Good luck.
狗日的俄罗斯杂种
Russian cocksucker.
操
Fuck!
不要啊
No!
赤手空拳 约翰
No more guns, John.
不用枪弹
No more bullets.
就你和我 约翰
Just you and me, John.
你和我
You and me.
发生什么了 约翰
What happened, John?
我们是专业人士 都是文明人
We were professionals. Civilized.
你觉得我是文明人吗
Do I look civilized to you?
回头见 约翰
Be seeing you, John.
是的
Yeah.
回头见
Be seeing you.
来吧 约翰 我们回家吧
Come on, John. Let's go home.
没事的
It's okay.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.